### **Denis Moroz**

moroz.denis@gmail.com http://www.linkedin.com/in/dmoroz/ https://github.com/denismoroz http://denismoroz.github.io/fend-p2-online-resume

### **Summary**

Principal software developer and senior software development team manager with more than 12 years of hi-tech industry experience. I am always open to new challenges, easily drill into new technologies and use the best practices to achieve the best result possible.

#### **Skills**

Python, C++, Android, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, PyCharm, AndroidStudio, Git, Celery, D3D.js, Jira, Asana, Ngnix, QT, Django, Flask, JavaScript, RabbitMQ, TDD, Agile, Linux(Ubuntu), Android, Windows.

## **Professional Experience**

Software Developer, US based startup 2014.01-present, remote consulting

- Designed mobile application backend and developed a database schema for MongoDB.
- Created REST API service to access backend functions using Flask.
- Archived reliable codebase support and minimized amount of bugs using of TDD for all backend API.
- Created web system administrator's interface using Flask and JavaScript to consume REST API services.

# Senior Python Developer, Mobsafety 2013.03-2013.09, remote consulting

- Responsible for Mobile Device Management solution for iOS and Android devices.
- Managed a team of four developers working on backend part of the project, used Agile.

# Python Developer, LatamIQ 2012.07 – 2013.02, remote consulting

• Built multiple backend services using MySQL that improved efficiency of economic indexes' analysis.

## Diango Python Developer, Keeyword.com 2011.09 – 2012.06, remote consulting

- Optimized PostgreSQL database schema to store at least 500k of keywords in one project.
- Reorganized HTTP server api to provide fast access to server data.

### Python/C++/C Developer, Visionica 2008.03 –2011.06, remote consulting

- Developed server side components for IP cameras recording system using Python and MySQL.
- Integrated Google ProtoBuffs to client side application written in QT.

# <u>C/Python/C++/Game Mods Developer, PlayAll 2007.05 – 2008.03, remote consulting</u>

- Developed several mods to control game flow for Q4, HL family, HL2 family, COD 1, COD2, UT2004.
- Implemented Linux Kernel Module and user mode application on Python to protect server side.

## <u>C++ Developer, Check Point Belrus, 2005.01 – 2007.08</u>

- fixed multiple security vulnerabilities in ZoneAlarm (multi-module Windows firewall application).
- Developed Linux Kernel module to filter and redirect http traffic.

#### **Projects**

Behaviour Cloning - part of Self-Driving Car Engineer Nanodegree Family location tracker for Android Casual game written in C++ for Android

### **Education**

2017, Udacity, Self-Driving Car Engineer Nanodegree – In progress

2015, Udacity, Front-End Web Developer Nanodegree. http://goo.gl/hPV8BJ

1998-2003, Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radio-Electronics.

Master of Science in Computer Science, specializing in Informational Security and Artificial Intelligence

#### Certification

June 2014, M101P MongoDB for Developers